The SCOAN Sunday Service
Oh God who created mountains of those days
Only You we give all of our praise
It’s You who created mountains of those days
Who then must be lifted high
If not our Heavenly Father
Who then must be given all of our praise
Who then must be lifted high
If not our Heavenly Father
Who then must be given all of our praise
Who then must be lifted high
If not our Heavenly Father
Who then must be given all of our praise
It’s You who created mountains of those days
Only You we give all of our praise
Good Morning, Church!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, “Be calm; Jesus is on the throne”.
Hallelujah!
Our viewers, thank you.
Whatever you are using to view us, we salute your faith.
Hallelujah!
Last week we talked so much about relationship and challenges for Christians.
We are going to land today.
Hallelujah!
1 Peter, chapter 2.
We start our reading from the beginning and later we will go to the proof text.
Hallelujah!
“Therefore, rid yourselves of all malice
and all deceit, hypocrisy, envy, and slander of every kind.
Like newborn babies, crave pure spiritual milk, so that by it you may grow up in your salvation,
now that you have tasted that the Lord is good.”
Indeed, the Lord is good.
Hallelujah; let's go to the proof text here - verse 15.
“For it is God’s will that by doing good you should silence the ignorant talk of foolish people.
Live as free people..."
That is, live and let me live; live and let others live. Think about that.
"...but do not use your freedom as a cover-up for evil.”
Hallelujah!
We title our message:
RELATIONSHIP UNDER REPAIR.
This text we read, you will also find it in other books:
1 Thessalonians 5:15.
Also when you look at the Book of Matthew 7. You take your reading from verse 12,
And the book of Romans, which will be the "landing" - Romans 3:10-15.
Our relationship is under repair of which everyone can agree with me.
Your relationship - everyone's.
You agree with me - your relationship is under repair.
It is not yet repaired completely, but is under repair.
Just like a vehicle you use,; you discover a fault; you have to give it to the mechanic.
When you ask, "Where is my vehicle?" - "It is under repair."
- "Where is my car?"
- "It is under repair."
We don’t have to look far to find things we do not like in our society.
Take note of that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Look through your immediate surroundings
and what you may see seems to be frightening.
Immediate, just look at your back. If not, because you are in the church.
Out there, at the bus stop, at the market, anywhere -
if you just stand, looking at your immediate surroundings,
you will probably see someone, who is ready to kill you if you are not leaving there.
Very very frightening.
Economic oppression – poverty everywhere.
Even if you have money, you cannot move freely again because of people that lack - you will be afraid.
What you have is not even enough to calm people around you.
Many of us - we don't live at our home anymore.
They say, "Are they at home?"
You call your wife, "Are they at home?"
"No, I will sleep there."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Political oppression – injustice and misrule everywhere.
You will hear some people say, "Will I vote? How will I vote?
How will I know that my vote will be this, that?"
Injustice and misrule everywhere, all over the world.
There is nowhere to run to.
In the past you could run this way but now it is like there is no way to run to.
Are you talking of religious oppression – intolerance and violence.
You just go anywhere and say, "What religion do you belong to? Are you this? Are you a Christian?"
Everywhere - fear.
Institutionalised corruption everywhere.
That is why the Book of 1 Peter 2:15 says that by doing good, you will silence the bad people around you.
In the face of all this, let us be known as people who are for good, not just against the bad.
Don't continue being busy talking, "It's not good".
If it’s not good, what have you done to change the bad you see?
If care is not taken, people will see you as a complainer.
Let us be known as people who are for good, not just against bad.
Because it is temptation; everything - I mean, we Christians today see temptations everywhere.
Something is there to make you curse, to make you talk.
Let us be known as people who are for good, not just against the bad in our society.
A little example can have a big influence.
You see me; for many years you people have been crucifying me, in the past.
When you move around many places of worship, you hear, "T.B. Joshua - rebuke him, ban him".
I was not engaged in, "You - you are not good. Ban him".
We are not banned, but you keep banning.
But here, we keep doing what is right, to change the bad we have seen.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
A little example can have a big influence.
Instead of being against your neighbour
because of bad behaviour and character,
we should try to do what is right to help him improve.
Instead of being against poverty, "See them; what are they doing; they are lazy!",
you should make a tangible contribution towards the society.
There are many people in your home, where you are living - their children are not going to school.
You always see them at home, but your children are going to school.
You don't need to see their parents, "What are you doing, little boy?"
"Oh, my mummy cannot pay my school fees, my daddy cannot pay."
"That is why I always see you around. Can you tell your parents that I want to support you?"
The child will run to the parents, "Daddy, mummy, this mister said he wanted to pay my school fees".
"Oh, thank you, sir."
Instead of saying, "What are these children doing? Look at these stupid children;
they are not going to school - stupid."
No!
When we see something that needs to be improved,
when we see something that needs to be removed,
when we see something in our society that needs to be changed,
when we see something that needs to be adjusted,
we must recognise our personal responsibility to do something about it.
"Ah - this is not right. This is how they have been doing that - it is very bad."
I'm not saying you should not condemn or criticize, but at the same time you should also look at
how that thing can be improved or changed.
This is where we are today, all over the world.
Everybody takes on the side of criticism, criticizing, "Bad, bad! It is not good!",
but we have never looked at the other side again.
When we see something that needs to be changed,
that needs to be adjusted,
that needs to be removed,
that needs to be improved in our society,
we must recognise our personal responsibility to do something about it.
As Christians, we have to take responsibility for our actions
because that is the only way we learn.
You must choose to do the right at all times
Though it’s contrary to what you really want
But the Spirit should lead you by and by
Then what counts is the essence of the true Church
That is the message to you.
After leaving the service today, you see many things under the chair - biscuits, whatever, we drop it.
You just leave it. You say, "Some people are coming to clean the church".
Which is...
As Christians, we have to take responsibility for our actions
because that is the only way we learn
and if we keep learning, we will improve.
If we improve, we become more mature in our Christian life
and in time, we will earn the right to operate on the level we deserve.
You have not operated on the level you deserve.
That is why you want to do something, "I don't understand my dream.
I don't know whether I should do this or not."
If you are operating on the level you deserve, there will be discernment.
When you move, there will be a force that will tell you, "Move this way, that way."
Not that you consult your neighbour to know where to go.
That is why we can do ten jobs at the same time; you are an architect, engineer, lawyer,
you are doing a lot of jobs, because you don't know the one that will bring breakthrough,
because you have not yet operated on the level you deserve.
You have so many jobs you are doing; you are the contractor, lawyer,
at the same time you travel to buy and sell.
You have so many business cards in your pocket; you don't know what to do because of failure.
Because you have not yet operated on the level you deserve.
Let me take you to the Book of Romans 3.
You take your reading from verse 10.
“As it is written: ‘There is no one righteous, not even one;
there is no one who understands.’”
There is no one who is righteous, not even one.
All have fallen short of the glory of God.
If that is the case, it means in this life, we are going to make mistakes.
When we do, as Christians, we must understand that mistakes are correctable.
We must think about what we did.
"Ah, yesterday, oh my God..."
You must think about what you did, reflect and ask yourself:
Is this the kind of person I want to be – a liar?
Is this who I am – a killer, a destroyer?
And so on and so forth.
Reflect and ask yourself:
Is this the kind of person I want to be – a liar, a destroyer, a smoker, a drunkard?
As a Christian?
Is this who I am?
Examining our life is a good thing.
Tell your neighbour.
[Examining our life is a good thing.]
I cannot hear you.
That is the key Jesus has given us.
Others – they don’t examine their lives.
That is why they do more of that mistake
but as true Christians, we examine our lives; it’s a good thing.
Few things are more dangerous than a person with an unexamined life.
Tell your neighbour, "Examine your life".
Again and again.
Examine your life.
Yes!
Is this the kind of person I want to be – a liar, a murderer?
This or that?
Is this who I am?
Let me quickly take you to the short note of Apostle Paul; that is the Book of Philemon 1:8-19.
That will be your manual to help you strengthen your relationship.
The question you need to ask yourself:
Do you easily get along with people
or are you guilty of the following I am about to mention, concerning the short note to Philemon?
Ask yourself:
Do you easily get along with people
or are you the type criticising instead of praising?
No matter what you do - you find you are not the one, you criticize.
There is nothing good to you, to find that you are not the one that did it.
You are the type that criticises instead of praising.
Instead of giving a tap, "Good. It's wonderful",
since you are not the one that did it, "No, this one is not good" - you are this type, are you?
Criticising instead of praising.
Using insensitive words.
Refusing to admit wrong.
"No, no..."
We are talking of relationship under repair.
Belittling others’ opinions.
"This is how to do. It is not like that. This is how we do it."
Making jokes at others’ expense.
Not listening to others.
This kind of attitude will wreck relationships
and hinder the healing of past hurts.
The Book of Philemon; chapter one - you take reading from verse 8 to 19 - that will really help you.
I pray the Lord will give you a hearing heart.
Viewers all over the world, I pray the Lord give you a hearing heart, in Jesus Christ’s name.
Amen.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT ROBERT BEGIER 11/08/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 16/08/2018